我们被监视着
We are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
第四季 第七集
疑犯追踪
快点儿  抓紧了  各位
Come on, any second, guys.
不是时候啊  哈罗德
Not a good time, Harold.
从来没"是时候"之时  肖女士
It never is these days, Ms. Shaw.
惠斯勒教授也同样
It's not as if Professor Whistler
有一堆期中考试卷要批
doesn't have a stack of abysmal midterms to grade.
我这边的情况要更加"争分夺秒"
My situation is slightly more time sensitive.
但号码还是跳出来了
And yet numbers keep coming.
业余
Amateurs.
这位新无关号码名叫
Our newest irrelevant is named--
肖女士  那是枪声吗
Ms. Shaw, is that gunfire?
说了我在忙了
I told you I was busy.
现在你得给我调出阴影地图
Now I'm gonna need you to call up that shadow map
获取纽约警局的调度信号
and access the NYPD dispatch feeds.
走走走
Go, go, go, go, go! Go, go!
全体人员注意  正在追踪黑色轿车
All units, pursuit in progress, black sedan.
追丢了  最后跟到了116西街
Lost them. Last seen on Westbound 116.
调度  1048  没有发现
Dispatch, 1048. No sign of them here.
好极了
Nice.
妞儿  击掌
Hottie. Up top!
我们说好的  记得吗
We had a deal, remember?
你及时出来  否则我走
You get out in time or I walk.
这就是后果
So now this happens.
天啊
Oh, God.
抱歉了  罗密欧
Sorry, Romeo.
看来我们是分手了
Think we just broke up.
纽约警察刚在东河发现了你的车
NYPD just found your getaway car by the East River.
希望不会查到你头上
Hope they can't trace it back to you.
我要是拷你  可就难看了
Be a shame if I had to slap the cuffs on.
你敢试试  你就难看了
It's be a shame for you if you tried.
这次是哪位
Now who's our boy?
托马斯·考罗拉
Tomas Koroa.
美国和西班牙双重国籍
Dual U.S., Spanish citizen.
三十一岁  未婚
31 years old, unmarried.
每年持短期商务活动签证到此
Spends part of each year here on a B1 visa.
干嘛
Doing what?
国际酒商
International wine dealer.
往来于纽约  伦敦  巴黎和迪拜
Divides his time between New York, London, Paris, and Dubai.
温馨提示噢  这瓶圣艾美隆
Now fair warning, this St. Emillion
会让你恨不得马上辞了工作
is gonna make you both wanna quit your jobs
直奔波尔多[法国南部]
and run way to Bordeaux.
到处旅行  进口外国商品
A lot of travel, importing foreign goods.
也许他是走私
Maybe he's wrapped up in smuggling.
有可能  不过我黑进他的手机
That's possible, but I didn't see anything fishy
没发现可疑之处
when I bluejacked his phone.
也许问题不是出在生意上
Then maybe business isn't his problem.
这种男人肯定满世界勾妹子
A guy like that could have a girl in every port.
可能是一脚踩的船太多了  要滚下水了
Maybe infidelity is about to spank him on the ass.
我在努力查找威胁  约翰
I'm just trying to identify the threat, John.
扮你的警察玩儿吧
You just go play detective.
我会盯好托马斯
I can keep an eye on Tomas.
知道了
I noticed.
好吧  那芬奇呢
All right, what about Finch?
他不是应该在查托马斯的网络数据资料吗
Shouldn't he be digging up Tomas' digital footprint?
他会的  不过他现在另有要事处理
He will, but he had other business to attend to first.
我们现在都是双重身份  记得吗
We're all two people now, remember?
你们乖乖去游乐场玩
If you play nice on the playground,
等会儿就给你们冰激凌吃  好不好
Then after you will have the ice creams, yes?
-好  -好的
- Yes. - Okay.
[法语]
孩子真可爱  但愿不是你的
Lovely children. Not yours, I hope.
放松  哈罗德
Relax, Harold.
我只是保姆
I'm just the nanny.
我这两周的第六个新身份
My sixth new identity in two weeks.
想必是必要的预防措施
A necessary precaution, I imagine,
鉴于你在选举事件中从撒马利亚人的特工手里死里逃生
after your close call with Samaritan's operatives during the election.
是必要  但累啊
Necessary but exhausting.
法版《欢乐满人间》保姆
French Mary Poppins BarBie
算是唯一的乐子了
is the only me that's been any fun.
不过要是孩子的父母知道我杀过多少人
Though I'm not sure how the parents would feel
就不知要做何感想了
if they knew how many people I've killed.
我们来这儿干嘛
So why are we here?
机器只告诉我来这个游乐场
The machine just told me to come to this playground
按你的计划行事
and follow your plan.
但愿是个好计划
Then let's hope it's a good one.
尼古拉斯·道森
Nicholas Dawson.
撒马利亚人非民主选出的州长
Samaritan's undemocratically elected choice for governor.
我们要扳倒他吗
Are we bringing him down?
遗憾的是  现在撒马利亚人
Unfortunately, now that Samaritan
已经派了格里尔先生前去联系
has sent Mr. Greer to make contact,
我们不能冒险接近这位新州长
We can't risk going anywhere near our new governor.
但我们可以破坏他的一举一动
But we can work to undermine every single thing he tries to do.
道森身为州长的第一步
And one of Dawson's first acts as governor
就是批款一千两百万给那个人
was to approve a $12 million grant for that man,
杰罗德·威尔金斯  软件工程师
Jerrod Wilkins, software engineer,
四十一岁  刚刚离婚
41 years old, recently divorced.
两周前
Two weeks ago,
威尔金斯辞去了收入颇丰的技术职务
Wilkins left a lucrative job in the tech sector
创建了一个慈善组织  名叫OTPS
to found a new charity called O.T.P.S.
做什么
Which stands for?
似乎无人知晓
No one seems to know.
OTPS没办公室  没网站
O.T.P.S. has no office, no website.
我们得查出他要用这些钱干什么
We need to find out what he plans to do with that money
并加以阻止
and put a stop to it.
爸爸  我要便便
Daddy, I made a boom-boom.
好
Okay.
好  去吧
Okay, just go ahead and--
等等  等一下  等一下
Wait, hold on, hold on.
等一下  别坐
Hold on, just-- don't sit.
现在知道我为什么是保姆了
And now I know why I'm a nanny.
[法语]再见  亲亲
Au revoir, mon cher.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
看起来你需要帮助
It seems to me as if you might need some assistance.
好了  六箱加利西亚白葡萄酒
Okay, so that's six cases of Albario,
十二箱教皇干红  我下次去[法国东北部]兰斯
12 of the neuf-du-pape, and next time I'm in Reims,
给你寄一箱那种巧克力
I'm sending you a box of those chocolates.
考罗拉先生那边进展如何  肖女士
And how is Mr. Koroa faring, Ms. Shaw?
发现威胁了吗
Any sign of the threat?
四个小时了  托马斯走出不到三百米
In four hours, Tomas has barely gone 900 feet.
一直不停地从一家餐厅到另一家餐厅
He just keeps moving from one restaurant to the next,
不停絮叨那些酒
blabbing about wine.
唯一能让我打起精神的就是他的
The only thing keeping me awake is his...
个性
personality.
是啊
Indeed.
稍等
Hang on a sec.
那姑娘今早在他身边出现过
That's the girl who checked him out this morning.
托马斯可能被跟踪了
Tomas may have a tail.
那几个工人今早也出现过
Same workmen from this morning too.
那不是跟踪
That's not a tail.
这是支杀手分队
We're looking at some kind of a hit squad.
再想想
On second thought,
也许不是要杀
this may not be that kinda hit.
十秒
Ten seconds.
九  八  七  六
Nine, eight, seven, six,
五  四  三
five, four, three,
二  一
two, one.
看来过双重生活的不只是我们啊  芬奇
Looks like we're not the only ones leading double lives, Finch.
托马斯不是酒商  他是大盗
Tomas isn't a wine dealer. He's a thief.
相当牛的那种
And a damn good one.
进出十秒内搞定
In and out in under ten seconds.
完美的飞速抢劫
A perfect smash-and-grab.
这位托马斯业务精通啊
Our boy Tomas really knows what he's doing.
你能否别如此兴致勃勃
Perhaps you could try not to sound quite so enthused.
犯罪是我的正职啊
Crime is my day job.
我  我只是欣赏他的技术啊
I'm--I'm just admiring his technique.
区域警觉系统发现了劫案
Domain Awareness caught the robbery,
但没有摄像头拍到托马斯及其团伙上车
but not camera saw Tomas and his crew getting into the car,
那车两天前就报失了
which was reported stolen two days ago.
这么说警察没查出他的身份
So the cops haven't I.D.'d him yet?
我非常肯定除了纽约警察
I'm fairly certain that the NYPD
还有其他人在找他们
isn't the only agency trying to find them.
他们的犯罪手法
Their modus operandi matches that
和一个屡犯大案的盗窃团伙相似
of a highly successful team of thieves
国际刑警称其为"墙孔帮"
that the Interpol has dubbed "The hole in the wall" Gang
原因一目了然
for obvious reasons.
在过去七年里
In the past seven years,
托马斯和他的团伙在四个大洲
Tomas and his team have hit over 50
窃取了超过50件高价值目标
high value targets on four continents.
托马斯可不乖噢
So Tomas is a real bad boy.
就是说可能他是行凶者
Which means that he is probably our perpetrator.
这种人也许会不惜杀人
Guy like this might be willing to kill
来达到目的
to take down his next score.
或者我们要找的是
Or our target might be someone
已经知道托马斯秘密的人
who already knows Tomas' secrets.
马可·耶夫蒂奇是托马斯团伙里唯一一个
Marko Jevtic was the only member of Tomas' crew
曾被抓住的人
to ever get caught.
他在布拉格一次犯案后被警方所抓
Picked up by the police after a robbery in Prague.
十个小时后  他死在拘留所
Ten hours later, he died in custody
死状可疑
under suspicious circumstances.
就是说托马斯不惜杀掉自己人
So maybe Tomas isn't above bumping off one of his own.
这伙人可一点都不可靠
They're not the most trustworthy bunch.
麦克斯·达尔格林
Max Dahlgren
亨里克·兰菲尔德
and Henrik Lengfelder,
都有一长串犯罪记录
both had well-documented issues with authority.
卡迪亚·罗德琴科则有很长的吸毒史
And Katya Rodchenko has a long history of drug abuse.
看起来我们无意中发现了
It appears that we have inadvertently captured
一群臭名昭著的罪犯
a group of notorious criminals.
我们要不要通知国际刑警算了
Should we turn them over to interpol and call it a day?
我们是阻止暴力的好吧
We're here to stop violence, okay?
不是找失窃珠宝的
not recover stolen jewels.
如果我们没查出楚托马斯的意图就行动
If we move before we know what Tomas is up to,
也许会出岔子啊
then this whole thing could go sideways,
我们就没机会阻止了
and we'll miss our chance to stop it.
你也没机会再看他了
Plus you won't get to look at him anymore.
你想逼我宰了你吗
Are you trying to make me kill you?
我们还是把专心解决
Let's try to stay focused on the murder
考罗拉先生即将犯下的谋杀吧
That Mr. Koroa is poised to commit.
要查出他的计划
To uncover his plans,
我们需要有人打入内部
we would need to have a man on the inside.
或者  一个女人
Or in this case, a woman.
我预定了顶层套房
I have reservation for penthouse suite.
安静  小熊
Oh, easy, bear?
这是缉毒犬
He's trained to smell drugs.
坐下  别动  安静
Sit, stall, stil.
纽约警察  女士
Yeah, NYPD, ma'am.
我要查看一下你的包
I need to take a look at your bag.
自便吧  我没什么要藏的
Enjoy yourself. I have nothing to hide.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
还说她不吸毒了
Told me she wasn't using anymore.
现在我们有麻烦了
Now we have a problem.
你猜怎么着  肖
Guess what, Shaw.
托马斯有麻烦了  你可以英雄救美了
Tomas has a problem, and you're the solution.
我去联系我的犯罪联络人
I'll reach out to my criminal contacts
安排见面
and set up a meeting.
不  不  不  没什么需要担心的
No, no, no, there is nothing to worry about.
我们会成功的
We are going to make this happen.
相信我  这绝对会是场重大变革
Trust me, this will be nothing short of a revolution.
州长和他的团队都参与了
With the governor and his people on board,
-我们的力量可以影响整个国家  -好了
- we have the power we need to impact the entire country, - All right.
-整个世界  -我通过婴儿监视器看到他了
- the world! - I've got him on a baby monitor,
你现在应该有信号了  哈罗德
and you should have a signal now, Harold.
看来你轻易赢得了
I take it you had no trouble ingratiating yourself
威尔金斯父子的欢心
with Mr. Wilkins and his son.
塞巴斯蒂安真是天使
Sebastian's an angel.
就是有点不受拘束
Just a little free spirit
要好好培养创造力
who needs his creativity nurtured.
而他爸爸  则有点A型性格
His dad, on the other hand, is a little more type-a.
OTPS的结果一出来
When O.T.P.S. starts generating results,
你会希望自己参与其中
you're gonna want to be on board.
查出他欺诈慈善的真正目的了吗
Any luck finding out what his fraudulent charity is really up to?
耐心点  哈罗德
Patience, Harold.
不然我就只好让你暂停一下了
Or I'll have to give you a time-out.
一切准备就绪了
We are ready to go right now.
好  进去了
Okay, we're in.
很快就能找到
It'll take me just a minute to locate--
天啊
Oh, my.
看起来威尔金斯先生的慈善
It turns out that Mr. Wilkins' charity
并不太欺诈
may not be so fraudulent after all.
OTPS的意思是"一学生一平板"
O.T.P.S. stands for "One tablet per student."
要发放平板电脑
A plan to issue free tablet computers
给全州每一个小学生
to every elementary school student in the state.
每台只要二十美元
For just $20 each,
我们就能给每个孩子
We can give every single child
一台自己的电脑
a computer to call their own,
上面装满了教育软件
loaded with educational software.
"撒马利亚人"提供的软件
Software provided by Samaritan.
每家一台平板
Tablet in every home,
摄像头对准了每一个孩子的脸
and a camera pointed at the face of every child,
"撒马利亚人"控制他们的所见  所学  所思
While Samaritan controls everything they see, learn, think.
刚说到魔鬼
Speak of the devil.
有东西正在黑我的手机
Something just started hacking my phone.
"撒马利亚人"  它利用了威尔金斯先生的电脑
Samaritan. It's coming through Wilkins' computer!
快离开
Get out of there now!
维罗妮卡  我电话打完了
Veronique, I'm off the phone.
你和塞巴斯蒂安
How are you and Sebastian getting--
漂漂
Pretty.
把你包里的枪拿出来放到我手上
Take the gun out of your purse and put it in my hand.
I can't give it up
To someone else's touch
还有你大腿上那把
And the one on your thigh.
Too much
I can't give it up
听说你在都柏林给奥班农做过事
I heard you did a job for the O`Bannons in Dublin.
如果我向派迪·麦凯恩问起你
If I were to call Paddy Mccann about you,
他会帮你说好话吗
will he say good things?
恐怕不会
Probably not,
派迪两年前就死了
since Paddy died two years ago.
但是你可以找西西里岛的恩佐·卡佩齐
But you can call Enzo Capizzi in Sicily,
或者问问洛杉矶的麦考雷我为他做的事
or you can check up on the work I did for Mccauley's crew in L.A.
或者也可以不要浪费时间
Or you can just quit wasting your time,
开始谈正事
and we can talk business.
难怪罗密欧强烈推荐你
I can see why Romeo recommended you so highly.
漂亮是女人的通行证啊
Nothing unlocks doors like a beautiful woman.
他挺辣呢
He's hot.
虽然不是"打包捆好扔到中情局安全屋
I mean, not "Hood and zip ties in a CIA safe house
纠缠十个小时"那种性感  不过
with ten hours to kill" hot, but...
酒保  两杯香槟
Bartender, two champagnes.
我懂
I kind of get it.
根  你在干什么呢
Root, what the hell are you doing?
哈罗德要我躲一阵子
Harold wanted me off the streets for a while
刚才遭遇了"撒马利亚人"
after my latest brush with Samaritan,
所以我想帮你看着点
So I thought I'd help keep an ear on you.
他毕竟是个危险的犯罪分子
He is a dangerous criminal after all,
我可不能忍受你被人伤害
and I just couldn't bear it if anyone hurt you.
除我之外  谁都不行
I mean, besides me.
那么
So...
马上就好
Coming right up.
你想让我干什么
What do you need me for?
我想让你干很多事
I can think of several things.
含蓄
Subtle.
我猜也是
I'll bet.
不过  我们现在还是
But, uh, for now let's just
专业点
keep it professional.
我猜昨天晚上的活只是测试
Now, I'm willing to guess that last night's job was a test
是为了记录纽约警察的反应时间
to check the NYPD's response time,
也就是说你  有更大的活
Which means that you have something bigger lined up.
瞧  这才叫含蓄
See, now that was subtle.
那么
So...
你准备好大干一场了吗
are you ready for another score?
不够含蓄了
That not so much.
也许吧
Maybe.
不过我不喜欢操之过急
But I'm not the kind of man who likes to rush.
一个完美的计划
A perfectly planned job
如同诱惑
is a kind of seduction.
长时间的关注  渴望
Hours looking, wanting,
在脑海中反复意淫目标
turning your target around in your mind.
然后
And then...
缓缓接近
you move closer,
擦肩而过
brushing past,
慢慢接触
making contact
观察反应
just to see what will happen.
当一切就绪
And when everything's ready
一切到位
and when everything is right,
所有的前戏
all of that preparation
将会换来天雷勾动地火的燃情一刻
pays off in one sudden, intense, crashing moment.
他不过
He's good.
不过这种台词
But a line like that
绝对打动不了你这种职业特
would never work on a trained operative like--
要换个地方吗
Do you want to get out of here?
好吧
Okay.
的确性感
Now, this is sexy.
计划下一次征服
Plans for your next conquest?
也许是
Maybe.
也许不是
Maybe not.
伙计们
Gentlemen,
我们得做个决定
we have a decision to make.
我们有人今天被抓了
One of us got arrested today.
只是毒品问题
It's just a drug charge,
但我们的行动可能被泄露了
but our operation could be compromised.
她的背景查了没问题
Everything about her checks out.
但无法确知
But there's no way for us to know
她是否为警察工作
whether she's working with the police or not.
下一票的风险很高
This next job comes with a very high risk factor,
但奖赏更丰
but it also comes with very high reward.
雇我们的客户愿意付给每人两百万
The client who hired us is paying $2 million each
偷一个保险箱里的珠宝
for the jewels inside of a single vault.
那么  我们是信她干了这票
So do we trust her and take the score,
还是处理了证据走人呢
or do we walk away and get rid of the evidence?
要我说干吧
I say let's go for it.
那开始干活吧
Then let's get to work.
计划已经定好了
The plan's ready to go.
只缺你了
All we need is you.
你打算什么时候开始
Okay, so when were you planning on doing this?
二十分钟后
20 minutes.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你是礼宾人员吗
Are you the concierge?
是的  有什么能帮您  小姐
Yes. How may I help you, miss...
史蒂文斯
Stevens.
我有些珠宝
I have some jewelry that--
可能价值比这酒店还高
it costs slightly more than this hotel,
我觉得要是放在房间的小保险箱里
and I don't think I'll sleep well
我恐怕睡不安稳
if it's in that little safe in the room.
你们有  更安全的地方吗
Could you offer me anything more secure?
当然
Of course.
我很乐意将您的东西存在酒店的保险柜里
I'd be happy to store your items in the hotel's vault.
我能先看看保险箱吗
And I don't suppose I could see this vault first, could I?
门是用高碳钢做的  时刻上锁
Bars are high-carbon steel, locked at all times.
保险柜本身是
The vault itself, it's--
后退  马上
Back up! Now! Now!
监控关了
Cameras are dead.
有你的片段已经删了
footage of you is being erased.
你真觉得能在警察来前打开它吗
You really think you can crack that before the cops get here?
有趣  但动静会很大
Cute, but that's gonna make one hell of a noise.
好了  可以走了
All right, good to go.
今天是退伍军人节
It's Veterans Day.
我们离无畏号博物馆的庆祝地点只有三条街
And we're three blocks away from the celebration at the Intrepid.
你现在肯定很骄傲是吧
You're pretty proud of yourself right now, huh?
看看吧
Let's see.
拖这一路触发了二重锁
The ride here tripped the relockers,
所以前门没戏了
so the front door's dead.
不过一路和混凝土的摩擦
But the friction with the concrete
把背板磨掉了  露出了焊接面
ground down the back plate, exposing the welds.
聪明啊
Clever boy.
让他来吧
Let him play.
你的工作结束了
Your work is done.
恭喜
Prost.
虽未阻止谋杀
We have yet to prevent a murder,
不过我们算是完成了"加上重大盗窃"
but we can add another grand larceny
这一光辉目标了
to our list of accomplishments.
我正在黑酒店的安保系统
I'm hacking the hotel security
看你们究竟偷了什么珠宝
to determine precisely what jewels you've stolen.
也许他们价值很高  托马斯不惜
Perhaps they're so valuable that Tomas is willing
背叛客户并杀掉同伴据为己有
to betray a client and kill his teammates just to keep them.
肖  你的约会怎么样
Shaw. How's your date?
不对劲  芬奇
Something's wrong here, Finch.
确实不对劲
Something's wrong indeed.
那个保险柜里唯一的东西
The only item in that vault
是酒店的一个客人昨天放进去的
was placed there yesterday by a guest of the hotel,
朱莉安娜·佩特洛娃博士  疾控中心的研究员
Dr. Juilianna Petrova, a researcher at the CDC.
她是四级传染病专家
She's an expert on level four infectious diseases.
肖女士  我不确定你们偷的是珠宝了
Miss Shaw, I'm no longer certain that you were stealing jewels.
我觉得托马斯也许
I'm kind of thinking maybe Tomas
根本不是行凶者  芬奇
isn't the perpetrator after all, Finch.
走
Go!
这里没人  肖
Place is clear, Shaw.
麦克斯和亨里克不在
No sign of Max or Henrik.
我和他俩合作了六年
Six years I've been working with those two.
六年  他们就这么把我卖了
Six years and they just turn on me like that.
赃物在吗
Any sign of the loot?
你在跟谁说话  我们到底在哪里
Who you talking to? And where the hell are we?
我查过你的地址  不在这儿
I checked your address out. This isn't it.
现在你要知道的唯一地址
Right now the only address you need
是那边酒柜的威士忌
is the whiskey in that cabinet.
给我调一杯特浓的  你也一样
So make mine a double, yours too.
保险柜里有个金属箱
Inside the safe, there was a metal case
标有"马尔夫"
with "Marv" on the label.
马尔夫
Marv?
反正东西被托马斯的兄弟拿走了
Whatever it was, Tomas' buddies have it now.
天啊  不妙了
Oh, dear, this is bad.
大事不妙了
This is very, very bad.
那些标签不是写"马尔夫"
Those labels don't say "Marv."
而是"马毒"
They say "Mar-v,"
"马堡病毒"
as in "Marburg virus,"
能引起出血性高烧
A viral hemorrhagic fever
死亡率接近九成
with a mortality rate approaching 90%.
埃博拉的邪恶双胞胎
It's like Ebola's evil twin.
佩特洛娃博士在乌干达
Dr. Petrova was in Uganda
搜集这种病毒的样本
collecting samples of the virus.
但是由于西非埃博拉病毒爆发
But due to the outbreak of Ebola in western Africa,
她把样本送回疾控中心的要求
her request to ship them to the CDC
被国安局拒绝了
was denied by Homeland Security.
不想让多月的研究付诸一炬
Rather than lose months of research,
佩特洛娃博士选择把样本非法偷运回美国
Dr. Petrova chose to smuggle them into the U.S. illegally.
现在却被人偷了
And now somebody stole them.
如果能让你舒服点的话
If it makes you feel better,
佩博士现在心急如焚
Dr. P's freaking out about it.
她刚向疾控中心的负责人自首了
She just turned herself in to her bosses at the CDC.
十瓶马堡病毒威力无穷
It would be difficult to overstate the degree
一旦被释放在纽约  后果不堪设想
to which we do not need ten vials of Marburg
我们不能让这种事发生
floating around the streets of New York City.
我们得尽快找到病毒和盗窃者
We have to find the virus and the people who stole it fast.
好  我去追踪麦克斯和亨里克
Okay, I'll track down Max and Henrik,
但我们得知道他们是替谁干活
but we need to know who they're working for.
可能和当初雇佣
It was probably the same client
托马斯的是同一个客户
who hired Tomas in the first place.
其他人不知道抢劫的事
Nobody else knew about the robbery.
再说  给钱他们俩去杀了托马斯
Plus, paying those two to kill Tomas
比付三个人的酬金要便宜
is cheaper than paying all three.
没错啊
It is.
那么
So...
你的客户是谁
who's your client?
你的又是谁
Who's yours?
你不止是小偷
You're not just a thief,
而且你肯定不是单独行动
and you're definitely not working alone.
所以我为什么要相信你
So why should I even trust you?
你想谈信任问题啊
You wanna talk about trust, huh?
你刚替极度危险份子
You just stole a very dangerous virus
偷了极度危险的病毒
for some very dangerous people.
如果我知道目标是什么
Look, I never would have done that
我是绝对不会动手的
if I knew what I was taking.
我不是圣人
I'm not a saint,
但有些事过了线
but some things are too far,
我这种人也不肯做
even for a man like me.
你的客户可没这么高的道德准则了
I doubt your client has the same high moral standards.
告诉我名字
I need a name.
没有
Never got one.
匿名邮件
Anonymous emails,
一次性转账的付款
payments by one-time wire transfer.
不提名字对大家都好
It's better for everyone if we don't use names.
但我会找到幕后黑手的
But I'm gonna find the bastard behind this.
我会把那些瓶子偷回来
I'm gonna steal those vials back,
要他付出代价
and I'm gonna make him pay.
你加入吗
You in?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我有个朋友
I have a friend
可以把那些匿名邮件
who can make those anonymous emails
变得没那么匿名
way less anonymous.
这里就是见证奇迹的地方
So this is where the magic happens.
租的一万平方尺办公室  装满了
Rented 10,000 square feet of office space and filled it
最先进的3D打印机
with state-of-the-art 3-D printers.
一千两百万几乎全都花在这上面了
Almost all the 12 million went to paying for these,
不过一旦运行起来
but once they're up and running,
我们就会在这里制造全部的平板
we'll be making all the tablets right here
在纽约
in New York.
这是样机
That's our prototype.
想像下全国的孩子们人手一台平板
Just imagine giving one of those to every kid in the state.
太棒了
Amazing.
我会告诉州长
I'll tell the governor
拨款得到了妥善使用
our grant money is in good hands.
你们为什么要装摄像头
Why are you guys putting up cameras?
我是公关办公室的  杰罗德
I'm from the public relations office, Jerrod.
州长想在我们的网站上
The governor wants a time lapse
放上你平板制作的定时拍摄画面
Of your tablets being made to put on our website.
或者一个邪恶的人工智能想盯紧
Or an evil A.I. wants to keep a close eye
它的洗脑工具
on its baby brainwashers.
我们入侵威尔金斯的电脑
Our intrusion into Wilkins' computer
肯定引起了撒马利亚人的警惕
must have put Samaritan on alert,
现在想做什么肯定更困难了
Making it that much more difficult to do what we must.
难是难  不过
Difficult but...
我们有办法的
we'll find a way in.
不过我们先要去买点东西
But first we'll need to go shopping.
找到病毒了吗  里瑟先生
Any progress finding the virus, Mr. Reese?
我找到了麦克斯和亨里克
I tracked down Max and Henrik,
但他们开不了口了
but I don't think they're gonna talk.
我查了他们的尸体
I searched their bodies.
没有手机  没有钱包
No phones, no wallets,
也没看到病毒
and no sign of the virus.
看来托马斯并非唯一
So it would seem that Tomas is not the only one
上了这位客户当的人
that this client has double-crossed.
如果这俩人知道他是谁
If these guys knew who he was,
或许别人也知道
maybe someone else does too.
你在浪费我时间
You waste my time.
那袋毒品是栽赃
Your drug charge is podrobka.
你定不了罪
You'll never make it stick.
我没必要
I won't have to.
现在是在调查凶杀案
See, it's a homicide investigation now.
你不想谈谈
You wouldn't want to tell me
你的朋友托马斯吗
about your friend Tomas, would you?
我从昨天就关在这里
I've been here since yesterday.
他的死和我没关系
I have nothing to do with his death.
我没说他是受害人
I never said he was the one who died.
这起凶案  死了两个人
The homicide I'm working, it's a double.
不管是谁雇你们仨杀掉托马斯
See, whoever hired you three to take out Tomas,
这才是他通盘计划
This is how they settled the check.
如果我是你
Now, if I were you,
我就会坐上第一班飞机
I'd like to be sipping a nice glass of champagne
喝着香槟  远走高飞
on our first flight to nowhere,
不会等着坐牢
Instead of a sitting duck in a jail cell.
不过  也许我在浪费你的时间
But maybe I'm wasting your time.
我喜欢托马斯
I like Tomas.
但公事归公事
But business is business.
你们怎么谈的
What was the deal?
每人再多五十万
Half a million extra each
给我  麦克斯和亨里克
For me, Max, and Henrik.
托马斯撬开金库  然后
Tomas cracks the vault and...
这是原本的计划
That was the plan anyway.
计划  谁的计划  客户是谁
Plan? Whose plan? Who was the client?
和其他活计一样
It was like the rest of the job.
一次性转账  匿名邮件
one-time wires, no-name emails.
不过这个人
But whoever he was,
他无所不知
he knew everything.
他知道托马斯是唯一一个
He knew Tomas was the only person
能偷取成功的人
to pull off a plan like this.
他也知道  如果托马斯知道里面是什么
He also knew Tomas wouldn't have done it
他不会去偷
if he knew what he was stealing.
他还知道你们仨
And he knew for the right price
出卖朋友的价钱
you three would turn on a friend.
哈罗德  我们到这里干嘛
Okay, Harold, why are we here?
面包屑  肖女士
It's bread crumbs, Ms. Shaw.
我追踪了托马斯和卡迪亚提供的
My attempts to trace the emails and wire transfers
邮件和转账记录
provided by Tomas and Katya
仍无法得知客户的身份
Have yet to reveal their client's identity.
但昨天那位客户转了一笔钱
But yesterday the client wired money
支付这里的储藏费用
to pay for storage at that address.
奈特和莫里斯公司
Knight & Morris,
纽约最安全的储藏公司
The oldest and most secure storage facility in New York,
存放物品包括从价值连城的传家宝
Housing everything from priceless heirlooms
到文艺复兴艺术品
to renaissance art.
在它九十五年的历史中
In their 95-year history,
从未被盗取过
they have never been robbed.
这里  简单点说  就是座堡垒
They are, simply put, a fortress.
所以无疑  病毒就在这里
So of course that's where the vials are now.
要知道它的确切位置
To locate them precisely,
我们仍要知道客户的名字
we still need to know the client's name.
混蛋
Son of a...
马可
Marko.
Marko?
马克·耶夫蒂奇
Marko Jevtic?
死在布拉格的搭档吗
The partner that died in Prague?
等等  你没杀他
Wait, didn't you kill that guy?
我从没杀过人
I've never killed anyone.
马可被抓后  我们想救他出来
We tried to spring Marko out after he got caught,
但太冒险了
but it was too risky.
那他要么是保存完好的尸体
So either he's a really well-preserved corpse,
要么是他装死逃了出来
or he escaped by faking his own death.
马可认为我们弃他于不顾
Marko thinks we left him to rot,
这出背后捅刀的戏是他的复仇
and this whole double-cross is his revenge.
复不复仇且不说  耶夫蒂奇手上有致命病毒
Revenge or not, Jevtic is in possession of a deadly virus,
而且我很想知道
and I would very much like to know
他对病毒有何企图
what he intends to do with it.
买家刚转了一半的货款
My buyer just transferred half the money.
包裹移交后我们就能拿到另一半
We get the rest when the package is delivered.
午夜行动
We move at midnight.
那我们就只剩六小时
So that gives us less than six hours
计划怎么抢劫这里
to figure out how to rob this place.
我们还有个麻烦  哈罗德
We have another problem, Harold.
我看到一个相关方的特工
I'm looking at an operative from the relevant side.
政府特工吗
A government agent?
你确定吗  你怎么知道的
Are you certain? How do you know?
因为是我训练的他
Because I trained him.
德文·格赖斯  深红6A
Devon Grice, crimson six alpha.
我认识他和他的搭档
I know him and his partner.
现在马可手上有了病毒
Now that Marko has the virus,
整件事升级为"相关"了
this whole damn thing just went relevant.
主要行动
目前威胁
事关国家安全
发现生物武器
马堡病毒  4类病原体
上传正常
Uplink's good.
国安局信号上线
NSA feeds online.
你怀念过去吗  布鲁克斯
You ever miss the old days, Brooks?
旧系统
The old system?
为什么
Why?
探索者2.0版选出的威胁多过旧系统
Research 2.0 targets more threats than the old system ever did.
这就是问题
That's just it.
以前  我们选定目标
Back then, we did the targeting,
我们的情报网做调查
had to scrutinize our own intel,
我们自己思考
think for ourselves.
我们打击目标时  我们知道原因
When we lit up a target, we knew why.
而现在不给号码去调查
Now instead of numbers to investigate,
而是直接干掉号码
we just get numbers to kill.
你不觉得奇怪吗
You don't think that's strange?
我们不是雇来动脑子的  格赖斯
We don't get paid to think, Grice.
主控者不会喜欢你刚说的
And Control wouldn't like what you're saying.
还记得靛蓝五号的事吧
You remember what happened to Indigo five, right?
我听说肖活了下来
I heard Shaw lived to fight another day.
没人幸存
Nobody lives,
问问题从来没有好结果
and no good comes of asking questions.
我们的命令是消灭所有目标
Our orders are to eliminate all targets
销毁全部病毒
and destroy every last drop of this virus.
晚上十点行动
We strike at 2200.
但要是相关方负责处理病毒
But if the relevant side is taking care of the virus,
也许我们的任务就结束了
perhaps our work here is done.
现在是"撒马利亚人"
Now that Samaritan is providing
向政府提供相关号码
the relevant numbers to the government,
插手这些行动很容易就会
any encounter with those operatives
遇上"撒马利亚人"的特工
into a run-in with Samaritan's agents.
为什么要冒不必要的风险
Why expose our operation to unnecessary risk?
因为我知道相关方如何运作  芬奇
Because I know how the relevant side works, Finch.
而且我认识格赖斯和布鲁克斯
And I know Grice and Brooks.
干掉马可及其手下之后
After they kill Marko and his men,
他们会找到所有与病毒失窃有关联的人
They're gonna track down everyone involved in stealing the virus,
然后全部斩草除根
and they're gonna kill them too.
托马斯想纠正错误
Tomas is trying to make this right.
虽然他是个罪犯
He may be a criminal,
但他罪不至死
but he doesn't deserve to die.
而且我们的目标不正是为此么
And isn't that what we're here for,
救他一命吗
to save his life?
她将住你了  芬奇
She's got you there, Finch.
再说  苏联人拿着武器化马堡病毒乱来过
Besides, the Soviets messed around with weaponizing marburg.
美国人还没有过
The Americans never did.
你真想让相关方
Do you really want the relevant side
拿到病毒吗
to get their hands on that virus?
或者让他们转手交给"撒马利亚人"
Or let them turn it over to Samaritan?
唯一能确保病毒被彻底销毁的方法
The only way to make sure those vials get destroyed
就是我们亲自动手
is to do it ourselves.
好吧  那就犯罪去吧
Fine, we'll commit your felony.
不过遗憾的是
But unfortunately,
我还得先着手另一项犯罪计划
I have another criminal act to attend to first.
格罗夫斯女士  我在路上了
Ms. Groves, I'm on my way.
很好  威尔金斯准备走了
Good, Wilkins is about to leave for the night.
制作中
And now we are cooking.
干得好  伙计们
Nice work, you guys.
第一批早上就可以完成了
First batch should be done by morning.
撒马利亚人瞎了  哈罗德
Samaritan's blind, Harold.
上吧
You're up.
进入系统
Accessing the system.
我大概需要十分钟
I'll need about ten minutes.
-有事吗  -我接到短信说
- Yes? - I got a text offering me 3,000 bucks
如果可以在五分钟内修复网络可以付我三千块
if I can fix your internet in the next five minutes.
真不想催你   哈罗德
I don't want to rush you, Harold,
不过撒马利亚人开始对付我们了
but I think Samaritan's onto us.
令人惊奇的是  格罗夫斯女士
Surprisingly, Ms. Groves,
这可不利于我集中精神
that does not help me concentrate.
哈罗德  我要做点你不喜欢的事了
Harold, I'm about to do something you're not gonna like.
不用了  我搞定了
No need. I'm done.
好了  进去  拿上病毒  出来
Okay, get in, get the virus, get out.
下个月在巴塞罗纳有活
Got a job in Barcelona next month.
我们要是能活下来  你该和我一起
If we live through this, you should join me.
我有工作了
I already have a job.
很奇怪  工资挺低
It's weird, the pay sucks,
不过
but, uh...
我们用得上你这样的人
we could use a guy like you.
我就位了  肖女士
I'm in position, Ms. Shaw.
我绕过了楼里的防火墙
I've circumvented the building's firewall
进入了安保系统
and accessed their security.
等你准备好就行动
Ready when you are.
长官  我们正在行动中
Command, we're in the middle of something.
知道了  深红六
We're aware, Crimson Six.
但有新指示
But new orders just came through.
你们被要求清除所有目标
You are instructed to eliminate all targets
保护试剂
and secure the vials.
我们接到的命令是摧毁病毒  不是
Our orders were to destroy that virus, not--
你们要拿到试剂并把他们完好无损地
You are to secure the vials and turn them over intact
交给已经在路上的联系人
to a contact already en route.
谁的联系人
A contact for whom?
你就需要知道这些  深红六
That's need-to-know, Crimson Six.
明白了吗
Do you acknowledge?
重复  明白了吗
Repeat, do you acknowledge?
明白
Acknowledged.
我们没上监控吧  芬奇
We're not on camera, are we, Finch?
还没
Not yet.
你该知道不止我们
And you should know that you're not alone.
相关方的朋友也在楼里
Our friends from the relevant side are in the building.
就是说指挥中心是在一个移动地点
Which means central command will be running op-sec
指挥行动
from a remote location.
如果你能看到我们
If you see us,
他们也能
so will they.
因此我在循环播放监控画面
That's why I'm looping the security feeds
掩盖你们的行踪
to cover your tracks.
马可的保险柜在你们左手第五个
Marko's vault is fifth on your left.
请快点  其他人离你们不远了
And please work quickly. The others aren't far behind.
不赖嘛
Not bad.
你那灵巧的双手打算如何打开那个呢
Now, how are those magic fingers gonna open that one?
抱歉  朋友
Sorry, my friend.
不像你们  我从不把重要物品留下
But unlike you, I don't leave important things behind.
我知道你会回来的  托马斯
I knew you would come for these, Tomas,
就像我知道你要是知道目标是什么
just like I knew you would never be bold enough
就是没胆动手了
to steal them if you really knew the score,
这还真是方便
which is convenient.
我的买家想病毒
You see, my buyer wants the virus delivered
在纽约交接
right here in New York city.
有什么比两个健康宿主
And who better to start a pandemic
更适合扩散传染病呢
than two healthy human hosts?
我们本来想救你出来的  马可
We were planning to get you out, Marko,
但我们听说你死了
but we got word that you died.
如果我知道你还
If I had known that you were still--
你知道伪装自己的死亡有多痛苦吗
You know how painful it is to fake your own death?
造成类心搏停止的药物对健康有多大的影响
What the toxins that simulate cardiac arrest do to your health?
这个只会更糟
This will be worse.
真不想打扰你  肖女士
I hate to trouble you, Ms. Shaw,
但是相关方的人员
but your counterparts from the relevant side
马上要把眼前的危险形势
are about to turn this perilous situation
推进得更加混乱了
into something dangerously chaotic,
所以可能会有点吵
so it may get a bit loud.
动手  约翰
Now, John!
搞什么
What the--
他们到底是谁
Who the hell are these guys?
训练有素的政府杀手
Highly trained government assassins
奉命杀人
with orders to kill.
让我跟你做这事不厚道啊  伙计
It's not cool you ask me to do this stuff with you, man.
不厚道
Not cool!
承认吧
Admit it,
我们在一起不错
We're not bad together.
我救了你小命你才这样说
You're just saying that because I saved your ass.
得了
Come on.
你  我  巴塞罗那  一笔一百六十万
You, me, Barcelona. Score worth 1.6 mil.
你确定不来吗
You sure you won't come?
你  我  这里  一个子儿没有
You, me, here, no pay.
我们最后都会死
We both eventually wind up dead.
你确定不待在这里
Are you sure you won't stay?
肖女士和克罗先生要走了  约翰
Ms. Shaw and Mr. Koroa are leaving, John.
考虑警察现在正赶过来
And considering that the police are en route,
现在也许是你撤离的好时机了
now might be a good time for you to make your exit too.
别动
Freeze.
肖
Shaw?
走
Go.
Go!
有人打电话说二楼着火了
I got a call about a fire on the second floor.
205室  3D打印机  东西没事吧
Suite 205, the 3-d printers, are they okay?
一整栋楼都没了  兄弟
Whole building's trashed, buddy.
不
No.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
一千一百二十万就这样没了
11.2 million up in smoke.
恐怕政府没法再给他更多的钱了
I doubt the governor could give him any more money
否则就会引起关注  撒马利亚人可不希望
without attracting attention samaritan doesn't want.
现在  我植入的蠕虫病毒
By now, the worm I planted will have destroyed
会彻底摧毁威尔金斯的设计
every last copy of Wilkins' design.
孩子们没有平板电脑了
So no tablets for the kids.
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
经典台词
Famous last words.
在我破坏打印机的时候
While I was sabotaging the printers,
我看了一眼平板电脑的编码
I took a quick look at the tablet's O.S.
有一行编码很奇怪
there was maybe one suspicious line of code,
我都不知道它有邪恶目的
and I'm not even sure it had any nefarious purpose.
哈罗德  你真认为撒马利亚人建这些东西
Harold, you really think Samaritan was building those things
是出于良善之心吗
out of the goodness of its own heart?
当卡斯特罗成为古巴的领导人
When Castro was coming to power in Cuba,
他做的第一件事就是建学校  很好的学校
the first thing he did was build schools, good schools,
以赢取人民的爱戴
so that the people would love him.
我知道撒马利亚人的动机无关道德
I know that Samaritan's motives are amoral at best,
但是威尔金斯先生想做好事
but the thing that Mr. Wilkins was trying to do
却被我们摧毁了
was an absolute good, and we destroyed it.
我不知道我们未来会变成怎样  格罗夫斯小姐
I'm not sure what we're becoming, Ms. Groves,
这让我疑惑
And it does make me wonder:
我们还要以正义的名义做多少坏事
How much wrong are we willing to do in the name of right?
我知道  机器不能在你耳边说话  让你挺难过
I'm sure not having the machine in your ear anymore sucks and all,
不过终于能偷偷吓你一跳还是挺爽的
but it is pretty great finally being able to sneak up on you.
我乐故我在
I live to amuse.
托马斯呢
Where's Tomas?
去巴塞罗那的路上
Halfway to Barcelona.
他给了我个挺好的提议
He gave me a pretty hard sell,
让我和他一起走
trying to get me to go with him,
有那么一刻  我就快答应了
and for a hot second, I almost did.
但是呢
But?
也许这里还有我在乎的东西
I guess there are things I care about here.
所以你跑来看我
And is that why you came to see me?
不是
No.
我需要你来翻译芬奇的指示
I need you to translate finch's instructions
怎么摧毁病毒
on how to destroy the virus.
这哥们就喜欢用大字眼的词儿
Dude never met a five-syllable word he didn't like.
全面净化
Full decontamination.
得花上一整夜
This could take all night.
我们还没发现病毒
We haven't recovered the virus yet.
你确定我们不需要追踪病毒了吗
Are you sure we shouldn't be tracking it down?
我们有新的命令
We have new orders
和一份南美的新号码列表
and a list of new numbers to take care of in south America.
问问题从来没有好结果
Nothing good comes out of asking questions.
记得吗
Remember?
正在删除
开始
Go.
覆盖
清除完成
数据恢复
文件重建
面部提取
额外目标检测
身份  不明
联系系统管理员